[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
His Majesty, the king, has arrived!
From this day on,
I will no longer worry about you.
Instead,
I will satisfy myself
with wishing you the best for the future.
If you will allow,
I want to take that wish
and place it in my flower.
For now, it is entrusted to you.
In the initial examination,
I asked in what ways the sacred herb
tobacco most becomes a loyal subject.
Out of many answers,
a certain man most commendably
expounded upon The Analects' teachings
that we be slow in speech
and swift in action.
This is that man's paper
from the palace examination.
I asked, "When a new branch
is born of an old tree,
what should it throw away,
what should it preserve,
and in what direction should it grow?"
Any fool could see this was a metaphor
for my current situation.
Well then,
what did he give for an answer?
In a place where
solemn scholarship is discussed,
he dared to criticize
the neglect of fact-based inquiry.
N… No, your grace.
That's not what I meant.
You wrote, "He who fears
to prune old branches
will risk endangering
the life of the entire tree."
Did you not?
Not only that, you rendered
this thought in frivolous prose!
This is water spilled on white porcelain,
it will quickly dry up and leave no trace.
This, however, is ink.
It will not come off so easily.
And he who spills it is stained.
Do you understand?
Now, whether the stain of these careless
words was made in water or in ink,
I shall have to keep a close eye on you.
Yes, your grace.
Follow me.
Hmm.
Well, my chief Eunuch,
do you surmise why,
despite this man's vulgar scribbles,
I elected to spare his life?
The manner in which he expresses
his thought may indeed be vile,
but he does not have the skill
to deceive me.
A king's life
must touch upon the entire world,
and keeping this piece of it close
will be useful.
He is not to be cast aside hastily.
Even if she is able to read
the vernacular script,
I worry Elementary Learning
may prove a bit…
If reading it is no trouble,
then understanding it
will be no trouble either.
You are right. That is true.
But she says
she has never properly studied before.
I worry it will prove
to be too challenging for her.
Concubine or not,
she is a member of this family.
That membership comes with responsibility.
At the very least,
she must cultivate the discipline to learn
by heart the propriety expected of her.
And so, until she does,
she will be looked down upon
wherever she goes.
That is true.
Well, we can't have people gossiping,
I suppose,
or claiming our concubine is ignorant.
Agreed.
Please entrust the matter to me,
my lord husband.
Though it may seem severe,
please remember that all of this
is for your own good.
Read the introduction
to Confucian learning,
and copy it 100 times.
100 times?
Young madam?
Young madam, are you asleep?
"Young madam"?
A letter for you.
A letter?
I apologize for breaking
your alarm clock earlier today.
I am most dismayed,
as I have unintentionally
damaged something precious of yours.
I sincerely beg your pardon.
How could I possibly make amends
for such a mistake?
Uh, I am Kwon In-ho,
youngest son of the Left State Councilor.
-My house is across from yours.
-In-ho?
You could pay me back for it.
Steady does it. Halt. And down.
So she's Catholic.
-Amen.
My cousin feared
you'd be out alone at this late hour,
but she felt a palanquin excessive.
She requested that I come instead,
as your journey back home
can be quite dangerous from here.
I am familiar with this household
and its activities.
All the more reason to escort you home.
When I was still a young boy,
my mother would always give me dried
mugwort leaves around this time of year.
They repel the troublesome mosquitoes that
come down from the mountain as it warms.
She feared that her only son's face
might be blemished by mosquito bites.
Here. Take it.
Dried mugwort leaves for the walk back.
If a mosquito bite
were to appear on your face,
would it not arouse suspicion
in your house?
I'm all right, my lord.
But it is not all right, is it?
If suspicions are aroused,
then your activities will be discovered,
and if that happens, not only I,
but everyone who gathered here
will be harmed.
So I ask you again,
would that be all right?
Hmm?
Go on, take it.
Madam.
The palanquin has just returned home.
And the councilor's daughter-in-law?
She returned home, I trust?
Actually, no. It returned empty.
They said that Lord Cho came out
and sent the palanquin back to us.
He should not have done that!
Go and have it sent back.
Go instruct them
to wait at the district entrance.
When she arrives, make sure
she goes the rest of the way hidden.
-Gye-hwa.
-Yes, ma'am.
The widow can't be seen with Cho Won.
If anyone so much as catches a glimpse
of them together,
the gossip in Bukchon
will go on without end.
You're right, madam.
What of the Left State Councilor
and Lady of the First Rank?
Has either of them yet returned?
No, ma'am.
Then go with all haste.
Careful.
The road is riddled with loose stones.
If you stumble and fall,
I will not be able to catch you.
So, please, watch close.
I will show you which way is safe.
Please, go on ahead.
I shall rest here a moment longer.
Ah.
Oh, no. Forgive me.
I had only considered my own pace.
As you wish,
we'll rest before we go on.
Tell me,
why do you yet live, my lady?
Had you taken your own life,
all the kingdom would have wept
at your virtue.
My mother-in-law is ill.
The household cannot spare another woman.
And with a new heir yet to be adopted,
I thought best to delay.
But now,
my mother-in-law's health improves,
and I will soon
be able to follow my husband.
Well then,
this is goodbye, eh?
I'm sorry, it's just…
You would not be able to do such a thing.
Especially if you're aware
of the Lord's teaching to cherish life.
I am aware of the teachings of the Lord.
It's not as strange as you might suppose.
I have always had a great interest
in various fields of knowledge.
Naturally, I've come across it
in my study of Western learning.
Hold, hold, hold, hold, hold.
My lord.
Lady Cho has ordered us
to carry the widow back.
Did she?
Heave ho. Onward.
Madam, the palanquin has returned safely.
My lady.
-Whoa, whoa, whoa.
-My lady.
Eun-sil.
Right this way.
Halt. Down.
INTRODUCTION TO
ESSENTIAL CATHOLIC TEACHINGS
"Thou shalt not kill."
I thought it was a spring day
I thought I would ride
A flower palanquin
Following my groom
On a swift horse
And walk the path
Of a woman
But you did not come
Only a plain palanquin
Covered in cotton cloth
Was there alone
I thought it was a spring day
Won, are you nervous?
Dear cousin.
Madam.
If you cannot sleep,
shall I bring you some tea?
Forgive me for causing you any worry.
I am all right.
You may retire.
How can she expect me
to write this 100 times?
It was the young master
who caused the commotion.
Why is she doing this to me?
Huh.
I am most grateful
that Your Lordship
would offer me an apology.
But you need not worry anymore
about the broken clock.
It is of no grave matter to me.
However, to tell it true,
my hand was slashed
upon the pieces of broken glass.
I had promised the elders of the family
to read the annotated vernacular edition
of Elementary Learning and study it
while copying down
the chapter on introduction
to Confucian learning 100 times.
But now I am unable to do so,
which is a pity.
I'm sure you are well aware, young master,
that a promise is a matter of great trust
between one member of a clan and another.
That book…
I have my copy somewhere.
It pains me to say,
but I fear I will now lose their trust.
Sixty-two.
Sixty-three.
I only wish I had brought them sooner.
I was glad to reread Elementary Learning.
For that, I have you to thank.
Sixty-five.
Sixty-seven.
I studied Elementary Learning
with my older brother.
Sixty-eight.
I was only five years old at the time.
He was like a teacher to me.
Seventy.
-Seventy-one.
-Indeed,
it is hard to believe
it has already been twenty…
-Twenty.
-…seven months.
-Twenty-seven.
-Or twenty-eight months.
-Twenty-eight. Twenty-nine.
-No, wait.
Twenty-six months.
Thirty.
Uh. Thirty?
-Anyway…
-Damn him.
-This year, the mourning period will end…
-I'll start again.
-…so I had decided to visit him.
-One.
Two.
Each step I took, one by one…
-One.
-…filled my heart with profound sorrow.
Hang on.
Did you do this on purpose or what?
Elementary Learning allows me to reminisce
of the times I spent with him.
In a most tender--
Uh…
My sincerest thanks.
But it seems there's a page missing.
I counted 99.
But I made sure there were 100.
It would appear not.
And I counted them over twice.
Would you make one more?
I would thank you.
Of course.
Yes, my lady.
I shall do it at once.
Um, here.
Oh.
Young Master In-ho. My thanks.
Oh, of course.
May I ask you what your name is, my lady?
Ah.
Yes, it's
So-ok.
My name is So-ok.
Ah. So-ok.
It is truly a most fitting name.
So-ok.
May I inquire, So-ok,
as to what brings you here,
to His Lordship's house?
Me? Uh…
Well, it's just I, uh…
-I mean--
-You see--
Are you by any chance,
the niece of Lady Cho who visited before?
I remember my mother telling me about you.
Then, you must be related
to Master Cho Won as well, no?
Yes, uh, so I am.
Oh, well, I'm afraid
I must head back inside.
-Wait.
-Oh.
I… I would keep you for one thing further.
Uh, I brought this from my house
without my mother knowing.
You said you cut your hand on the clock.
Ah…
If you gather some like this
and apply it to the cut,
it should be healed in no time.
You were hurt because of me,
so I must bring the remedy,
-should I not?
-Mm-hmm.
I will borrow it, only for three…
No. For only two days.
Two days from right now,
when the two hands of the alarm clock
stretch out flat like the horizon,
let us meet here again.
Uh… Yes.
Good night.
Mind your step.
When the two alarm clocks… No.
When the hands of the alarm clock
stretch flat…
Let me see here.
Now, how long has it been
since we last drank together?
Hmm?
Oh, yes.
Is it not the first time
since we drank when I was at Hwaseong?
Yes, that's correct.
You were there
for the relocation of the royal tomb.
Hmm.
You know, I must say,
I found myself quite unable to comprehend.
Comprehend what?
The king cherished his son.
To seal his cherished son
in a mere rice chest,
that I cannot comprehend.
He's a father.
How could he do that
to his precious child?
-I can't speak for the father…
-Hmm.
…but I think I can understand the heart
of the son who longed to defy him.
Until the day he was sealed away.
To a son,
a father can be a world
he can never reconcile with.
Indeed. Mmm. You speak it true.
It would seem the prince…
was much like myself.
Two men…
defeated before
the dreaded name of "father."
Make sure it is clear.
That's how my dear cousin
prefers his broth.
Yes, madam.
If I ever imbibe so much again,
I will be changing my family's name
to Cho.
I would not do so myself,
that name has made you Minister.
Oh, my head.
Why did you not stop me?
My lord! My lord! My lord!
There's a herald out front!
A herald from the palace wishes to enter!
-A herald? From the palace, you said?
-Yes, my lord.
I thought the king was upset with me.
I thought I was to be dismissed.
Have I not always advised you
not to worry over things
that lie outside your control?
It is just as I thought.
His Majesty knows your true heart.
You really think so?
Oh. Go now. He is here.
Yes, yes.
Goodness. I should not be sitting.
My word.
I am prepared. Recite it at once.
-My lord, I--
-Come and recite.
Has His Majesty not summoned me?
There's not a moment to lose.
That is not so.
His Majesty
has summoned a man named Cho Won.
Then, I am not summoned?
Cho Won, come forward!
His Majesty orders you to read this.
Another order of paper has just come in.
We work through the night!
Can I help you, sir?
Who are you?
Ah, I… I'm in the right place, at least.
Take it easy now!
At this pace, I doubt this paper
will be fit for sale come the morning.
Damn you and your idle talking!
Well, sir. What brings you here?
In the last petition,
you claimed your family was starving.
Well, how have you been faring since?
No better.
Because of your petition,
several officials have faced punishment.
So, I came by to see if any of them
had tried getting revenge.
Hmm…
I received your confidential message
and took the papermaker's words to heart.
Therefore, I have commanded
for all those involved
to be summoned to Hanyang at once.
Forgive me, your grace,
but it seems the matter concerns
more about papermaker Gil-san.
I assumed as much.
Corruption, by nature,
is wont to spread like wildfire.
I humbly apologize, your grace.
You have no need to apologize.
-Left State Councilor.
-Yes, your grace?
I shall entrust that man with a task.
I humbly await Your Grace's command.
I confide this to you in trust.
What I have begun in Hwaseong
is no less than an act of filial piety
to honor my late father.
That is the reason
I shall not tolerate
any form of injustice,
no matter how trivial.
My lord husband,
what has caused you
to take up smoking again?
This book…
Cho Won wrote this book, did he not?
The other day,
when we briefly passed each other
on the road,
I felt the faint smile on his lips
bore a trace of excessive lust.
It was rather disturbing.
Did you not say that Lord Cho Won
had fallen out of favor with the king?
Hmm.
It would seem…
his fortunes will soon be
quite the opposite.
So I have asked him
to be our guest here a while.
That is all you need to know.
This is all we need to pack?
You rascal.
You seemed almost pleased at that.
It's just over there. We'll be fine.
Are you leaving?
Oh, my.
Have you come to see me off, my lady?
I am most humbly honored.
You are talented indeed.
Somehow, you got inside that house.
The heavens must be lending a hand.
Although,
who is this assistance for?
Could this blessing
be meant for you in the end?
Or indeed for me?
If I had to guess,
I'd say your debauchery
was too much for heaven.
Too much, you say?
Well, now, when this little wager
of ours is over,
you'll have to see for yourself, cousin.
Until then.
Madam, a messenger just delivered this.
It's from the tobacco shop,
but he said it was intended
for Lord Cho Won.
Shall I go after him?
Since it came from that shop,
I assume it is tobacco.
But that red silk vexes me greatly.
I shall deliver it to him.
Take it to my chamber.
Yes.
You have no idea how excited I am.
Right this way.
This is the rear garden.
Now that I have you in my house,
you had best put away
any thought of escape.
There are so many things
I wish to ask you, hear from you,
and learn from you, of course.
Oh, um, these quarters are where
my sister-in-law has been residing.
Since my brother's passing,
she has been in mourning,
but you know this from meeting her.
A tragedy.
Please follow me.